<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:8080/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:8080/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-06-29T03:00:35+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:8080/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Juliette</title><subtitle>Graduate June 2017</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Third Year in Review</title><link href="http://localhost:8080/year%20in%20review/2017/06/15/year-in-review.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Third Year in Review" /><published>2017-06-15T18:06:08+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-15T18:06:08+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:8080/year%20in%20review/2017/06/15/year-in-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:8080/year%20in%20review/2017/06/15/year-in-review.html">&lt;p&gt;This year was probably the most successful year of my college career. I made huge strides in my technical knowledge and capabilities. I was put on meaningful programming projects during co-op. I took every opportunity to learn and challenge myself technically and personally. I attended hackathons to teach myself teamwork and new technologies. I took on the position of Logistics Director for the UC hackathon to practice my leadership and management skills. I made this website to teach myself web development. My hard work has really paid off and I feel much more secure in my technical and leadership capabilites now than I did a year ago. The University is starting to notice too: this year I received the Mantei/Mae Award, a scholarship given to the top ~15 students in the EECS department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have found my accomplishments to be very helpful in the co-op job search, and I intend to continue pushing myself to become an even stronger programmer and an even better communicator in preparation for the full-time job search. I have learned a lot about what types of programming I enjoy doing, and what I am not so fond of. I have also gotten a glimpse at just how much I have left to learn, and I plan to continue using personal projects and hackathons to get experience in these areas if classes are not an option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This upcoming year, I will continue my work with ACM and RevolutionUC. I plan to lead the Logistics team again, and we hope to continue increasing the size of the event every year. I will start co-op with a new company and hope to prove myself as a strong developer and a good addition to their team. One thing I would like to learn this year is full-stack web development. I am comfortable now using HTML and CSS to build a static responsive website, but I don’t know anything about connecting a site to a database, using Express for routing, or really anything more than the basics. My personal projects this year are going to revolve around becoming a more capable web developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall I had a great year and I am looking forward to my upcoming semesters. I am taking a lot of interesting techincal courses and am really looking forward to my next co-op job. I think I will enjoy my classes and co-ops more and more as I become stronger technically and get increasingly challenging work.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="year in review" /><summary type="html">This year was probably the most successful year of my college career. I made huge strides in my technical knowledge and capabilities. I was put on meaningful programming projects during co-op. I took every opportunity to learn and challenge myself technically and personally. I attended hackathons to teach myself teamwork and new technologies. I took on the position of Logistics Director for the UC hackathon to practice my leadership and management skills. I made this website to teach myself web development. My hard work has really paid off and I feel much more secure in my technical and leadership capabilites now than I did a year ago. The University is starting to notice too: this year I received the Mantei/Mae Award, a scholarship given to the top ~15 students in the EECS department.</summary></entry></feed>